mappingmegan.com 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy - Mapping Megan

Mapping Megan found at https://www.mappingmegan.com (“Website”) is governed by the following privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”).

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what personally identifiable information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this Website.

#### Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website

We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address when you voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, or subscribing to a newsletter.

#### Information We Collect from Others

We may receive information about you from other sources, for instance if you choose to link your Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, Linkedin and/or Google accounts in the website field when commenting. The Website utilizes social media commenting systems, so if you choose to comment on a Website post which has been shared on social media, your comment may appear on the blog post as well.

#### Automatically-Collected Information

We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.

#### Cookies

We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

### We may use the information collected in the following ways:

➡ To operate and maintain the Website;

➡ To create your account, identify you as a user of the Website, and customize the Website for your account;

➡ To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;

➡ To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;

➡ To respond to your comments or inquiries;

➡ To provide you with user support;

➡ To track and measure advertising on the Website;

➡ To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

#### Google Analytics

This service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.

#### Mail Chimp

This service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications.  Please refer to Mail Chimp’s privacy policy for further information.

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

If you leave a comment on the Website, certain information like your name may be publicly visible. Your email address will never be available publicly. At your option, you may also add an avatar, a profile description, and a link to your website.

Users may see your username, avatar, profile description and website information.

The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

#### Display Ads

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies, as noted above.

#### Retargeting Ads

From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

#### Affiliate Program Participation

The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

Mapping Megan is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.  As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

#### Newsletters

On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns.

Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

#### Opt-out

You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at megan@mappingmegan.com to be removed from our mailing list.

#### Access

You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to megan@mappingmegan.com

#### Amend

You may contact us at megan@mappingmegan.com to amend or update your personal information.

#### Forget

In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to megan@mappingmegan.com

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at megan@mappingmegan.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

At any time, please contact us at megan@mappingmegan.com for questions related to this Privacy Policy.

Last updated: May 11, 2018.

## [Important Things to Know about Backpacking in Nepal](https://www.mappingmegan.com/backpacking-guide-nepal/)

Posted by on 6:27 pm in [Adventure Travel](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/interests/adventure-travel/), [Blog](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/blog/), [Budget Travel](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/interests/budget-travel/), [Nepal](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/world/nepal/) | [2 comments](https://www.mappingmegan.com/backpacking-guide-nepal/#comments)

Backpacking in Nepal is an incredible adventure. From intensely chaotic cities, to medieval architecture, and Himalayan trekking, Nepal might be hard to get to, but you’ll probably find that it’s even harder to leave.

Nepal is well set up for independent travel, and has become a mecca among the backpacking scene. It is a culturally rich country that will absolutely enchant you, though it’s definitely a destination that requires prior planning to ensure your safety and comfort.

The following is a backpacking guide to Nepal, with all of the essential info you need to know when planning your trip.

## [The Best Destinations for Whale Watching Around the World](https://www.mappingmegan.com/best-destinations-for-whale-watching-around-the-world/)

Posted by [Meg Jerrard](https://www.mappingmegan.com/author/megan_claire/ "Posts by Meg Jerrard") on 12:04 pm in [Blog](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/blog/), [Eco Tourism](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/interests/environment/) | [6 comments](https://www.mappingmegan.com/best-destinations-for-whale-watching-around-the-world/#comments)

Whale watching became a trend in the 1980’s, as a way to try and influence the debate over whaling. Back then the concept of whale watching was written off as a ‘stupid idea’, but nowadays it’s anything but.

In trying to change the social acceptance of whale hunts, a group of fairly savvy conservationists realized that there is nothing more remarkable than seeing a whale in the wild, and saw a world where whales would be more valuable to an economy alive, than hunted.

Ever since then, whale watching has grown into a 2.1 billion dollar industry, and almost every country with a coastline has jumped in on the action.

While it was conservationists who pioneered the whale watching tourism trend, researcher Roger Payne credits only one group for the development of whale watching: the whales themselves.

Described as nature’s best self‐publicists, whale watching is now taken seriously as an economic activity globally. So, do take a look at this list before booking your whale watching holidays.

## [Book List: Inspiring Travel Reads From Kick Ass Female Authors in 2019](https://www.mappingmegan.com/book-list-inspiring-travel-reads-from-female-authors/)

Posted by [Meg Jerrard](https://www.mappingmegan.com/author/megan_claire/ "Posts by Meg Jerrard") on 6:41 pm in [Blog](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/blog/), [Book & Film Reviews](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/reviews/book-reviews/) | [2 comments](https://www.mappingmegan.com/book-list-inspiring-travel-reads-from-female-authors/#comments)

We’ve well and truly entered an age of female empowerment, and as far as 2019 is concerned, I’m dubbing this the year of the wander woman.

Over the past few years women have tipped the scales to become the majority of travelers over men. We’re taking more active adventures, and saying no to sipping cocktails on the beach. And we’re not letting age be a limiting factor (the world is now being taken OVER by amazing traveling grandmas).

Some women are doing it solo, some are traveling with their families, and some are dragging along their husbands (lucky guys!). Some have quit their jobs and sold everything, while others travel while holding down a job and a mortgage.

Women these days who want to travel aren’t letting anyone tell them how it should be done, they’re making their journey their own. But even better, they’re writing about it to inspire the rest of us.

If you’re looking for a great travel memoir to add to your summer reading list, make sure you pick up one of these; brand new titles from kick ass women who haven’t been afraid to follow their dreams.

I’ve been absolutely captivated by their stories!

## [5 Reasons to Visit Komodo National Park (Indonesia)](https://www.mappingmegan.com/reasons-to-visit-komodo-national-park-indonesia/)

Posted by [Meg Jerrard](https://www.mappingmegan.com/author/megan_claire/ "Posts by Meg Jerrard") on 4:58 pm in [Adventure Travel](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/interests/adventure-travel/), [Blog](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/blog/), [Indonesia](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/world/indonesia/) | [4 comments](https://www.mappingmegan.com/reasons-to-visit-komodo-national-park-indonesia/#comments)

In the Indonesian archipelago, between the islands of Sumbawa and Flores, lies Komodo National Park. It’s the only place on Earth you can have a close encounter with a Komodo dragon, a unique lizard species often referred to as the last living dinosaur.

In an effort to conserve this rare creature and its natural habitat, the Komodo National Park is listed as a UNESCO World Heritage Site. The park consists of three major islands (Komodo, Rinca and Padar) that are home to over 2500 of these impressive and fearsome creatures.

Though Komodo is much more than it’s famous wildlife; the islands also boast some of the world’s best diving and snorkelling spots, and landscapes so dramatic the island was recently named one of the world’s “7 New Wonders of Nature.”

With a new airport in Labuan Bajo, on the neighbouring island of Flores, access to Komodo is now just a boat ride away. Here are just five of the many reasons you’ll want to discover the magic this Indonesian gem has to offer.

## [Your Privacy is at Risk When You Travel: Here’s Why You NEED a VPN](https://www.mappingmegan.com/protect-privacy-when-travel-why-you-need-a-vpn/)

Posted by [Meg Jerrard](https://www.mappingmegan.com/author/megan_claire/ "Posts by Meg Jerrard") on 1:15 pm in [Blog](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/blog/), [Travel Tips](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/travel-tips/) | [0 comments](https://www.mappingmegan.com/protect-privacy-when-travel-why-you-need-a-vpn/#respond)

When you travel to another country, it’s good practice to be vigilant and aware of your surroundings to keep yourself safe from possible threats. But what about online threats?

Did you know that when you travel to other countries, in many cases, you are more vulnerable to online threats than you are at home?

For many of us, when we connect to the Internet, we don’t think at all about how we’re connecting. We just do. The devices we use even connect themselves to the Internet sometimes, for all kinds of things like backups and automatic updates.

While that’s just the nature of the way we live now, it doesn’t mean you don’t need to be careful to protect yourself and your information. Because most internet connections we used by travelers are open public networks, this puts our personal data at risk.

Abstinence has never been a practical solution, so the one way to solve this is by using one of the best free VPNs. Here’s why you need to be traveling with a Virtual Private Network (VPN) for the sake of your data.

## [How to Get Around Censorship of the Internet: Travel With a VPN](https://www.mappingmegan.com/get-around-censorship-of-the-internet-travel-with-a-vpn/)

Posted by [Meg Jerrard](https://www.mappingmegan.com/author/megan_claire/ "Posts by Meg Jerrard") on 8:44 pm in [Blog](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/blog/), [Travel Tips](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/travel-tips/) | [0 comments](https://www.mappingmegan.com/get-around-censorship-of-the-internet-travel-with-a-vpn/#respond)

The Internet and its uses are wondrous. And you may think that no matter where you are in the world, you can access whatever you want as long as you there is an available internet connection, right?

Unfortunately, that’s wrong.

While the internet might hold the answer to everything, there are actually a lot of restrictions and legalities involved with what kinds of content you’ll be able to access in specific parts of the world.

Not every country believes in providing free and open internet to their citizens, and you might find when traveling that your internet access is limited, and the government has blocked certain websites.

This means that if you’re traveling internationally, you might want to do a little research and prepare yourself for the browsing and streaming complications that might arise while you’re on your trip.

## [Ways to Stay Entertained on a Long Distance Bus Ride](https://www.mappingmegan.com/ways-to-stay-entertained-on-a-long-distance-bus-ride/)

Posted by [Meg Jerrard](https://www.mappingmegan.com/author/megan_claire/ "Posts by Meg Jerrard") on 4:01 pm in [Blog](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/blog/), [Road Trips](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/interests/road-trips/), [Travel Tips](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/travel-tips/) | [0 comments](https://www.mappingmegan.com/ways-to-stay-entertained-on-a-long-distance-bus-ride/#respond)

Let’s be honest – no-one particularly enjoys a long bus ride. It can be crowded, too hot, and most all, incredibly boring.

Though despite being confined to one seat for hours at a time, there are definitely ways to distract yourself so that the time flies by.

Dreading an upcoming long distance journey? These activities will keep you entertained throughout the long-distance bus ride.

## [7 Ways Travel Can Improve Your Mental Health](https://www.mappingmegan.com/travel-can-improve-your-mental-health/)

Posted by [Meg Jerrard](https://www.mappingmegan.com/author/megan_claire/ "Posts by Meg Jerrard") on 7:13 am in [Blog](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/blog/), [Healthy Travel](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/interests/health/) | [5 comments](https://www.mappingmegan.com/travel-can-improve-your-mental-health/#comments)

The stresses of everyday life can be overwhelming. From family and work issues to commuting, daily chores, illnesses, home maintenance and plenty of other concerns, the grind of day-to-day life can pick away at your mental well-being.

If you ever feel stuck in life, or tired of your current situation, it is sometimes best to get away. A vacation may sound at first like you are running from your problems, but the truth is quite the opposite.

For the reasons listed below, you may be surprised at the wonders a good holiday can do for your mental health.

## [Reasons to Rent a Car in Los Angeles](https://www.mappingmegan.com/rent-a-car-in-los-angeles/)

Posted by [Meg Jerrard](https://www.mappingmegan.com/author/megan_claire/ "Posts by Meg Jerrard") on 8:27 am in [Blog](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/blog/), [Road Trips](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/interests/road-trips/), [United States](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/world/united-states/) | [4 comments](https://www.mappingmegan.com/rent-a-car-in-los-angeles/#comments)

LA is one of those iconic destinations that every traveler should experience at least once in their lifetime; a sprawling urban metropolis that is deeply creative, and bursting at the seams with culture, personality, and access to Mother nature.

Whatever draws you to LA, whether it be laying underneath palm trees on a golden coast, the glitz of Hollywood, upmarket bars and boutiques, or lacing up your hiking boots for treks across the rugged mountains, LA truly has something for everyone.

But with such a huge range of experiences, in a city more than ten times the size of Paris, the most difficult part of planning isn’t going to be figuring out what to include on your itinerary; it’s going to be how to maximize your time.

For that reason alone we highly recommend renting a car.

## [Reasons You Shouldn’t Visit Tokyo Without a Trip to Tokyo DisneySea](https://www.mappingmegan.com/reasons-you-should-visit-tokyo-disneysea/)

Posted by [Meg Jerrard](https://www.mappingmegan.com/author/megan_claire/ "Posts by Meg Jerrard") on 7:11 am in [Blog](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/blog/), [Family Travel](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/interests/world-family/), [Japan](https://www.mappingmegan.com/category/world/japan/) | [8 comments](https://www.mappingmegan.com/reasons-you-should-visit-tokyo-disneysea/#comments)

My first ever trip overseas was to Japan when I was 15. It was a language immersion trip with my High School, and my name was pulled out of a hat for one of the coveted places.

And while this introduction to travel involved many cultural highlights like attendance at a local school, a homestay with a Japanese student, and traveling to Hiroshima to place 1,000 cranes, the one day I was most looking forward to was Tokyo Disneyland.

Fastforward 15 years, and I would find myself traveling back to Tokyo, with the sole purpose of visiting Tokyo DisneySea®. And, in a country where embracing worlds of fantasy is part of the cultural fabric, I discovered the same sense of pure joy and wonder as I had felt at age 15.

Tokyo DisneySea is an incredible theme park inspired by the myths and legends of the sea. And in the lead up to my trip, fellow adults would lose their composure and absolutely gush about how incredible their time at the park had been.

In the fierce debate about the best Disney park in the world, I feel confident awarding the title to Tokyo DisneySea. Here’s why.
